Rick Murdock

Web Developer

Franklin, TN 37067 (615) 513-4313 rick.murdock@live.com rickmurdock.com github.com/rickmurdock linkedin.com/in/rickmurdock

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 20+ years of experience building and supporting a variety of systems for the insurance, financial regulation, and retail industries. Past computer science graduate and recent graduate of The Iron Yard coding school. Retooling my career with modern technologies for front-end web development.

TECH SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- jQuery

- React
- Redux
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- SQL

- Node.js
- NPM
- Git/GitHub
- Unit Testing
- Responsive Design

EXPERIENCE

The Iron Yard

5/2017 – present

Front-End Engineering Student

Nashville, Tennessee

• The Iron Yard is a 12 week, full-time immersive code school providing a full stack-foundation of both front-end and back-end fundamentals, including a language specialization in JavaScript with ReactJS.

LifeWay Christian Resources

5/2005 - 3/2017

Software Engineer

Nashville, Tennessee

- Assisted with support of WinDSS point of sale system for 170+ retail book stores.
- Worked with team to upgrade Python retail back office system from Django 1.4 to 1.8., including adding functional test and improving code readability.
- Built and maintained all company benefit file feeds for both open enrollment and regular payroll processing. Worked with both HR personnel and external vendors.
- Provided main support for MeetingTrak camps and events registration system. Assisted
 internal customers with production support issues. Worked with team to gather
 requirements and seek out a web based solution to replace this system.

Senior Application Developer

Chicago, Illinois

- Led project to rewrite an existing ASP web based system to ASP.NET using VB.NET,
 Oracle and stored procedures. System was enhanced to provide additional functionality.
 This project involved developing design specifications based on requirements from both internal and external users (U.S. futures exchanges and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission).
- Worked on a team to convert an existing mainframe member registration system to a new Online Registration System (ORS). Worked on all phases of the system with users from all departments over a three year period. Provided ongoing support and added new enhancements. Development was done in Visual InterDev with an Oracle database. This new system allowed members to get temporary registrations the same day instead of waiting a few weeks.
- Assisted users of the Special Committee on Registration Fitness issues. Extracted and prepared data for an outside consultant to analyze.
- Built an Access application to generate a series of Firm Directory reports. This allowed an old application to be removed from the mainframe.

United Insurance Company of America

10/1990 - 6/1999

Senior Programmer / Analyst

Chicago, Illinois

- Worked with a team to complete necessary Y2K changes to Oracle Forms 4.5 modules and SQR reports in preparation for company Y2K Certification.
- Designed and developed Oracle Forms 4.5 modules for a new Policy Administration System to replace the existing mainframe Register System. Worked with users at all levels of the company to create business rules and specifications.
- Converted an Employee Front End System from Forms 3.0 to Forms 4.5. Designed an Agency Tracking and Licensing System that was later added to the Front End System.
- Used Oracle Forms 4.5 to create a GUI prototype for a new Life Claims System.
 Participated in the full life cycle from analysis to implementation of this client/server system with an Oracle database.
- Worked with outside vendor, using CompuSet, to convert pre-printed insurance policies to an Automated Policy Printing System.
- Supported Cybertek Auto-Issue System in COBOL and Assembler. Added new insurance products and provided user support.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida - Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, May 1990 Orlando, Florida

The Iron Yard - Certificate, Front-End Engineering, August 2017 Nashville, Tennessee